Guide to the Undergraduate Studies, Yale College, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Undergraduate Studies, Yale College, records of the dean
1956-1985
RU 214
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
25.25
The records consist of reports, committee records, correspondence, regulations, and chronological files of Martin Griffin as dean of undergraduate studies of Yale College. Included are records on the Executive Committee, the Yale College Council, the residential deanships, discipline, the Buckley Amendment, athletics, and prizes.
Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office
Griffin, Martin I. J. (Martin Ignatius Joseph), 1933-1988
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-B (YRG 9-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of Yale College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, committee records, correspondence, regulations, and chronological files of Martin Griffin as dean of undergraduate studies of Yale College. Included are records on the Executive Committee, the Yale College Council, the residential deanships, discipline, the Buckley Amendment, athletics, and prizes.
Deans (Education); Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale College Council; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Awards; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Student housing
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1973-1980; Accession 1982-A-027
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Arnstein Report: Admission of Women to Yale, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class meeting times, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coeducation report, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - College credits: class of 1976, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - College Deans, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
  - College Deans (walker Committee), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Council of Masters, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 10)
  - Credit-fail option, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Energy: class hours and extracurricular activities, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Executive Committee: master sheets, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Freshman mailings, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Housing, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 18)
  - Introductory seminars in the colleges (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Leave of absence figures, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Military leave of absence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Minority Orientation Program, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 23 - 25)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 26 - 28)
  - Residential College Deans, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Parking regulation drafts, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Police reports, 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 32 - 36)
  - PROP, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Report of Summer Term Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Residential College Deans, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Residential College Deans, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Residential College Masters, 197-1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Scholars of the House, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 42 - 43)
  - Space, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Special courses in absentia, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Student elections, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Student records, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 47 - 49)
  - Summer Programs, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 50 - 51)
  - Summer term, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 52 - 53)
  - Summer term and academic regulations, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Undergraduate admissions, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Yale College Council, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 56 - 57)
  - Yale College Dean's office, 1974-1979 (Box 7, Folder 58 - 61)
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1971-1983; Accession 1982-A-028
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - Undergraduate Regulations
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1975 text (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1978-1979 "my copy" (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1979-1980 (final copy) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1981-1982 Text of edition (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Academic Regulations
    - 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Buckley Amendment, 1977 June - 1980 September (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Student records, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1963-1981; Accession 1983-A-052
  - "A Handbook for the Director of UndergraduateStudies" 81 pp, 1976 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Revised Handbook for the Director of Undergraduate Studies" revised, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale College Course of Study Committee. Subcommittee on Special Programs, 1973 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Course of Study Committee. Subcommittee on Special Programs. Speical Courses in the Humanities, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Reflections on the Scholar of the HouseProgram'' Elting Morison. "Some comments on..." B. C. Cannon., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report of a Joint Committee-of the Executive Committee and the Course of Study Committee on Acceleration--3 copies, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale College Committee on Honors and Special Projects, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report on the Residential Deanships, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee on the Size of Yale College. Reports, correspondence, minutes, material background, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 12)
  - Residential College Deans--minutes of meetings, 1963, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13 - 17)
- Records, 1970-1982; Accession 1983-A-053
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
  - Academic Regulations, Summer Term, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Regulations, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acceleration, etc Johns Hopkins' Report, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acceleration: Proposal for Revised Policy, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Additional Credit for Language Courses, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Admissions Advisory Committee, 1973-74 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Admissions Profile, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Advanced Placement Program, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African Relief Organization, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Athletic governing board, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Athletics, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Athletics, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Athletics: Ivy Group, 1977-78 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Athlll!tics: Ivy Group. Minutes of, 1977-79 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Athletics: Ivy Group Policies, 1979-80 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Athletics: Ivy Group Policies, 1979-80 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Athletics: Ivy Group Policies & Membership, 0 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Auditing, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - B.A.-H. A. Program, 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bicentennial Commission, 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - British Studies, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Bursar Bills, 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Bursar's Hold, Spring Term, 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Bursar's Hold, Fall term, 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bursar's Hold, Fall term, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bursar's Hold, Spring Term, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bursar's Hold List: correspondence, 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bursar's Letter, Summer, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Bursar's Office, 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bursar's Office, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Calendar, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Calendar, 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Calendar, 1976-78 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Calendar, 1978-80 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Calendar, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - C. E. E. B., 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Class of 1977: General Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - College Credits, 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - College Credits:Class of 1977 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - College Credits: Class of 1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - College Credits 1 Class of 1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - College Credits: Class of 1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - College Credits: History, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - College Entrance Examination Board, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - College Masters, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - College Seminar Study Group, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - College Seminars, 1977_78 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Colloquium on Teaching, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Combined Sciences Major, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Combined Sciences Major, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Complaints, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Complaints, 1978-79 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Committees
    - Coordination and Eligibility Committee, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1967-68 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Departmental Student Advisory Committee, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Executive Committee, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Executive Committee, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Executive Committee, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Executive Committee, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Executive Committee: Degrees and prizes, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Executive Committee: Summer Term, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Executive Committee: Summer Term, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Fulbright Committee, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Fulbright Committee, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Fulbright Committee, 1977-78 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Joint Committee of Masters & Deans, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Joint Committee of Masters & Deans, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Joint Committee of Masters & Deans, 1977-78 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Joint Committee of Masters & Deans, 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Saybrook Master's Search Committee, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Standing Committees, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Standing Committees, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Teaching and Learning Committee, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Teaching and Learning Committee: report, 1975 February (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Connecticut Conference of Independent Colleges, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Conversion of Advanced Placement Into College Credit, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Council of Masters, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Council of Masters, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Council of Masters, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Council of Masters, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Course Numbers, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Courses for Double Credit, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Courses in Professional Schools, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Credit Fail Option, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Deadlines, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Dean's Excuses (Fake Forms), 1976 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Departmental Examinations, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Directors of Undergraduate Studies, 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Directors of Undergraduate Studies, 1979-80 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Directors of Undergraduate Studies:Handbook1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Distribution: Harvard Core Curriculum, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Distributional Requirements, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Distributional Requirements, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Divisional II Major, 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Divisional I~I Major, 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Early Concentration, Misc., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Eli International, 1975-76 (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Elizabethan Club, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Enrollment, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Enrollment, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Financial Aid, 1979-80 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Five-Year B. A. Program, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Five-Year B. A. Program, 1973-75 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Five-Year B. A. Program: Memorandum on Year Back, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Freshman Counselors, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Freshman Counselors, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Freshman Counselors, 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Freshman Literature, 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Financial Aid, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Griffin, Martin: Personal, 0 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Health Services, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Housing, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Housing, 1977-78 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - International Baccalaurate Examinations, 1974-76 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Internships, 1980-81 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Internships, 1981-82 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Junior Year Abroad, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Leave of Absence Packet, 1975-76 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Majors Book, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - Major Statistics: Course Regulations, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - Minutes of Dean's Meetings, 1971-72 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Minutes of Dean's Meetings, 1972-73 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - Minority Students, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979-80 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980-81 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1981-82 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - Miscellaneous Letters from Other Universities, 1972-73 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - Multiple Credit (Labs and Languages), 1971-74 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Phelps Association, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Police Reports, Campus, 1970-71 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Police Reports, Campus, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - Police Reports, Campus, 1975-76 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - Police Reports, Campus, 1980-81 (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - President's Harassment Procedure, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - Prop, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - Prose Style, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - Psychology & Biology Major, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Registration, 1975-76 (Box 10, Folder 150)
  - Readmission Policies, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 151)
  - Resident Fellows, 1978-79 (Box 10, Folder 152)
  - Residential College Seminars, 1975-76 (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - Science Courses for Non-Scientist, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 154)
  - Scholars of the House, 1971-72 (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - Scholars of the House, 1972-73 (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Scholarships aod Loans, 1973-74 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Shoplifting, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Special Courses in the Humanities, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 159)
  - Special Courses in the Humanities, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 160)
  - Special Programs, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - Special Programs: Correspondence, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - Special Student, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - Special Students, 1975-76 (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - Special Students on Leave, 1973-74 (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - Special Students on Leave, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 166)
  - Special Tutorial Courses, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 167)
  - Student Affairs, 1975-76 (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - Student Organizations, 1973-74 (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - Student Organizations, 1974-75 (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Student Performance at Yale, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 171)
  - Study of the City Major, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 172)
  - Summer Language Institute, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 173)
  - Stunmer Program and Summer Term, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - Summer Term, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - Summer Term Bulletin, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 176)
  - Summer Term Enrollment, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 177)
  - Transcendental Meditation, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - Telephone Toll Abuse, 1977-78 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - Transfer Students, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - Transfer Students, 1975-76 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - Tutoring Program, 1979-80 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Undergraduate Admissions, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Undergraduate Organizations, 1979-80 (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - University, Lecture Committee, 1971-72 (Box 12, Folder 185)
  - U. S. Naval Academic Foreign Affairs Conference, 1979-80 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Veterans Administration Benefits, 1971-73 (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Vietnam Tablet, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - Women's Intercollegiate Athletics, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 189)
  - Writing: English Department Proposal, 27881 (Box 12, Folder 190)
  - Writing Intensive Courses, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 191)
  - Writing Prose, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - Yale College Council, 1974-75 (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - Yale College Council, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 194)
  - Yale College Council, 1975-76 (Box 12, Folder 195)
  - Yale College Council Survey, 1974_75 (Box 12, Folder 196)
  - Yale College Dean's Office, 1979-81 (Box 13, Folder 197)
  - Yale College Dean's Office, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 198)
  - Yale College: Enrollment Size, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 199)
  - Yale College Internship Program, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 200)
  - Yale College Printing Service, 1976-77 (Box 13, Folder 201)
  - Yale College Printing Service, 1976-77 (Box 13, Folder 202)
  - Yale College Printing Service, 1977-78 (Box 13, Folder 203)
  - Yale College Transcript: Ad Hoc Committee, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 204)
  - Yale College Transcript: Final report, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 205)
  - Yale Station, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - Yale Summer Programs, 1979-80 (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Yale-Summer Term and Yale Health Plan, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 208)
  - Student Records, 1973-74 (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - Student Records, 1980-81 (Box 13, Folder 210)
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1956-1984; Accession 1984-A-033
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Executive Committee
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 6)
    - Master sheets, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 9)
    - Minutes, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10 - 17)
    - Minutes, 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18 - 26)
  - Combined B.A. - M.A. Program: General and actioms, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 27 - 39)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 40 - 41)
  - Council of Masters, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 42 - 43)
  - Yale College Council, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 44 - 47)
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1973-1985, Accession 1989-A-038
  - Residential Deanships
    - 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 9)
    - Annual Report, 1979-1985. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 11)
    - Appointment Procedure, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Description, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 15)
    - Executive Committee, Role in, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Events of Spring, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Inventory, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Miller Report, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Review Procedure, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20 - 22)
    - Rooster, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Walker Report, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee
    - General: Legal Decision re: Liability concerning liquor, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Presidents Harassment Procedure, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - False Statements (Cabranes letter), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Post-Woodward Committee, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Report on Actions, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - General Descriptions, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Computer Facilities/Rules, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Faculty Legislation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Spring Term, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Disciplinary Procedure, undated, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 37 - 40)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - University Wide Tribunal, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Discipline: Report of the president's Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Seymour Portrait, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Student Complaint Procedures, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Members, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Acedemic Business, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Ad Hoc Committee (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 50 - 54)
    - Actions, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Grievance Procedures: President's Statements, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Bladder Ball Recommendations, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Take-over" Scenario, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Members, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 61 - 62)
    - Sub-Committee OE Late Work, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - University Tribunal Interim Statement, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Academic Business Working Document, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Statement on Actions, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Statements on Penalties, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Procedures (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Discipline: University-wide Tribunal, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Harassment Procedures, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Summer Term, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Master Sheets, 977-1918 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Disciplinary Procedures (General: Florida), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Grasso-Thalheimer, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Master Copies, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 75 - 76)
    - President's Committee on Discipline Report, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Gallo (wine), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Grievance Procedures, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Academic Dishonesty, 1959-1976 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Guidelines for award of prizes (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Grade Greivances, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Jerisdiction (letter to Cabranes), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - students' Rights, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Communication with Parents (letter from Cabranes), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - General, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Yale Law Journal: Article on Injunctions, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Financial Aid Regulations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Financial Regulations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Dining Hall Regulations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Extra curricular Activities, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Parking Regulations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Dormitory Regulations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - University Health Services, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Anti Divestment Rally, 1979
    - Chairman's Copies, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Draft statements of various members of Committee, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Bladder Ball (see also: Box 5 folders 218-226), 1976-1977
    - Bill, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Branford, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Committee on Discipline, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Chairman's Statement, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Deans Office's fetter to Students, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Discipline at Yale, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Disciplinary withdrawls, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Executive Committee: Letter to HOT, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - The Graduate Student, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Group Report, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - The Judge's Decision, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Matter relating to Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Meeting with Students, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 119 - 120)
    - Original of Chairman's Statement, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Originals of Charge, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Petition by Students, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 123)